    <sect1 id="xyster.orm.lookup">
        <title>Lookups</title>
        
        <para>Lookups are special objects that can be added to an entity type.
            The allow for runtime generation of values based on the contents of
            an entity.  They also allow setting values back to the entity.
            There are two different lookups that come with Xyster.</para>
            
        <glosslist>
            <glossentry><glossterm>Xyster_Orm_Entity_Lookup_Date</glossterm><glossdef><para>Can generate <classname>Zend_Date</classname> objects based on a date field in an entity</para></glossdef></glossentry>
            <glossentry><glossterm>Xyster_Orm_Entity_Lookup_Enum</glossterm><glossdef><para>Can generate <classname>Xyster_Enum</classname> objects based on the value of a field in an entity</para></glossdef></glossentry>
        </glosslist>
        
        <para>The best place to instantiate and add these lookups is the <methodname>init</methodname>
            method in your mapper classes.  You can create your own lookup classes
            by implenting <interface>Xyster_Orm_Entity_Lookup_Interface</interface>.</para>
        
        <sect2 id="xyster.orm.lookup.date">
            <title>Xyster_Orm_Entity_Lookup_Date</title>
            
            <para>The date object takes two or three arguments.  The type of 
                entity that the lookup supports, the name of the field where
                the date value is stored, and optionally the name of the property
                on the entity that will invoke this lookup (by default it's the
                name of the field appended with 'Date').</para>
                
            <para>When a new <classname>Zend_Date</classname> object is stored to
                the lookup property, its value will be written to the original 
                date field on the entity (additionally, you can specify the format).</para>
        </sect2>
        
        <sect2 id="xyster.orm.lookup.enum">
            <title>Xyster_Orm_Entity_Lookup_Enum</title>
            
            <para>The enum lookup takes between 3 and 5 arguments.  The type of 
                entity that the lookup supports, a <classname>Xyster_Type</classname>
                object that represents the type of enum class, the name of the
                field where the lookup value is stored, optionally a flag for 
                specifying whether the entity value is used as the enum name or
                value, and optionally the name of the property on the entity
                that will invoke this lookup (by default it's the name of the 
                field appended with 'Type').</para>
                
            <para>When a new <classname>Xyster_Enum</classname> object is stored
                to the lookup property, its value (or name) will be written to
                the original value field on the entity.</para> 
        </sect2>
    </sect1>